In this demo we'll be creating a program that utilizes if else statements.
Once you're ready, fire it Visual Studio Code, and let's go!
Once Visual Studio Code loads, click on your demo directory, and we're doing if-else,
so click on if-else, and then finally double click on if-else.go.
So we have some existing functionality here, and we're going to be utilizing it within our program.
So the first thing we'll do is create some quiz scores, so we'll have quiz 1, quiz 2, and quiz 3.
And we'll set those scores to 9, 7, and 8.
Next, we're going to create an if statement.
So we'll have if quiz 1 is greater than quiz 2.
We'll print on a message.
We'll then continue with an else if, so quiz 1 is less than quiz 2.
We'll print a different message.
Finally, we'll have an else keyword, and then the last message will be the scores are equal.
So this first check, check to see if quiz 1 is greater than quiz 2.
The next one is quiz 1, less than quiz 2, and the last one will cover any other cases.
Since we all already covered greater than and less than, the last case will be checking to see if it is equal to.
Next, we'll do, we'll call our average function.
So if the average of quiz 1, quiz 2, and quiz 3 is greater than 7, then we'll print on a message.
And if it's not greater than 7, we'll print out a different message.
When we run this program, we should get the output here.
So quiz 1 scored higher than quiz 2, because quiz 1 is greater than quiz 2.
And we should get here acceptable grades printed out for the average.
Because the average of these is going to be higher than 7.
So let's hop into a terminal and give it a go.
We'll run this one with go run dot slash demo slash if dash else.
And so there we go.
We have quiz 1 scored higher than quiz 2, and we have acceptable grades.
This concludes the demo on if else.
I'll see you in the next presentation.